21年前，国际空间站的第一个舱段发射升空
21 years ago, the first module of the International Space Station was launched into orbit.
过去二十年，它成为了上百名宇航员的家
Over the last two decades, it has been the home to hundreds of astronauts,
完成了无数可以改善地球上的生活的科学研究
conducting an incredible amount of scientific research to help us improve life on Earth.
但国际空间站还剩多少时日？
But how long does the space station have left?
当它完全退役时会怎样？
And what will happen when it eventually retires?
本期视频我们将了解国际空间站的未来
In this video, we’re going to look at what the future holds for the ISS.
我们还将了解卫星们退役后会去哪
We’re also going to look at where satellites go to retire
以及NASA未来在地球与地球以外地方的空间站计划
and NASA’s plans for future space stations around Earth and beyond.
在过去20年，国际空间站逐渐成长到一整个橄榄球场的大小
Over the last 20 years, the ISS has grown to be the size of an entire Football field,
环绕了地球超过十万圈
completing more than 100,000 orbits around Earth.
然而，建造国际空间站的材料和结构终究会老化
However, the materials and structures that make up the space station will eventually wear down,
而那时对宇航员就不安全了
to the point where it becomes unsafe for the astronauts.
更不用说NASA每年要花大约40亿美元来运营国际空间站
Not to mention, it costs NASA around 4 BILLION dollars each year to operate the ISS
且目前空间站的经费会在2024年截止
and the current budget for the space station ends in 2024.
NASA打算在2028年将项目退役
NASA are looking to retire the program in 2028
从而给未来更令人激动的深空任务留出资金
in order to free up funding for more exciting missions into deep space.
但一旦NASA决定让国际空间站退役
But once they decide to retire the ISS,
他们就要面临着把这个太空中最大的物体“弄走”的挑战
they will have the challenging task of removing the world's largest spacecraft from the sky.
根据外层空间条约，每个国家有责任让各自的舱段离轨
According to the Outer Space Treaty, each country is legally responsible for deorbiting their own modules.
很多人建议把各个舱段分别带回来
Many have suggested that each module should be brought down separately
然后在地球上组装成一个博物馆
and reassembled to become a museum piece here on Earth.
但唯一能做到此事的火箭是早已退役的航天飞机
However, the only vehicle capable of doing something like this was the Space Shuttle,
且即便如此也需要27次任务才能把它们全部带回地球
and even that would require 27 missions to carry each segment back to Earth.
所以最有可能的办法就是直接让国际空间站离轨
The most likely solution is to deorbit the space station
让它掉回太平洋中称为“尼莫点”的地方
into an area of the Pacific Ocean known as Point Nemo.
这块区域与任何文明都要相距超过1000英里(1600公里)
This area is over 1,000 miles away from any civilization,
使其成为丢弃退役航天器的最安全的地方
making it the safest place to discard retired spacecraft.
仔细看船上是谁
这片区域遥远到离那最近的人是上空飞过的空间站里的宇航员
This area is so remote, that the closest humans are actually the astronauts aboard the ISS,
因为他们离那里只有250英里(402公里)
which flies at just 250 miles above the surface.
从人类航天起步以来，已经有200多颗卫星在此寿终正寝
Since the beginning of spaceflight, over 200 satellites have ended up in this location,
包括在2001年坠落于此的苏联/俄罗斯的和平号空间站
including the Russian Mir Space Station, which was deorbited here in 2001.
当卫星高速再入地球大气层时
When a satellite reenters the Earth’s atmosphere at high speed,
巨大的热量和压力会让多数卫星完全解体
the intense heat and pressure is enough to completely disintegrate most satellites.
同时，和平号空间站也是最大的离轨航天器
At the time, the Mir Space Station was the largest spacecraft to be deorbited,
其中一些较大舱段“逃过一劫”，留下1800英里(约2900公里)的残骸
and some of the larger sections managed to survive reentry, creating a trail of debris 1,800 miles long.
与和平号一样，国际空间站不是第一个空间站，更不是最后一个
Just like Mir, the ISS wasn’t the first Space Station, and it won’t be the last.
在国际空间站服役之前，苏联/俄罗斯就成功运营了7个自己的空间站
Before their involvement with the ISS, the Russians had successfully operated 7 of their own space stations.
当国际空间站退役后，俄罗斯打算把自家舱段分离掉
Once the ISS is retired, the Russians plan to remove their own segments
用其组建新的空间站
and use them to make a new space station.
与此同时，中国航天也在研发他们自己的空间站
Meanwhile, the Chinese Space Agency have been developing their own space station,
预计2020年发射，三年内组装完成
which is scheduled to be launched in 2020, taking 3 years to fully assemble.
国际空间站快要退役，又没有替换新空间站的计划
With the ISS coming to an end and with no plans to replace it,
NASA期待有私人公司能接管或者自行研发空间站
NASA have looked towards private companies to either takeover the space station or develop their own.
若太空叉的Starship发射成功
Once SpaceX has Starship up and running,
它就可以经过改装后变成太空叉自己的空间站
it could be modified and turned into its own space station,
一个Starship里的空间就比整个国际空间站的大
with a single Starship providing more space than the entire ISS.
然而，如果太空叉不能找到让空间站盈利的运营模式
However, unless SpaceX find a way of making space stations profitable,
那他们就很难会去冒这个险
it’s unlikely that they will take on such a challenge.
而NASA则把眼光放到了月球那边
NASA on the other hand currently has its eyes set on the Moon.
他们在研发月球轨道空间站，预计2024年发射
They are developing a Lunar space station which is scheduled to be launched in 2024.
宇航员会在那个空间站停留更长的时间
Astronauts will spend long periods of time on this space station,
来了解人体在离开地磁场保护受到更强宇宙辐射后的变化
to see how the human body reacts to the intense radiation outside of Earth’s magnetic field.
该空间站还会作为深空运输载具的停靠点
This space station will also be the holding point for the Deep Space Transport vehicle,
未来可以用于送人类往返火星
which is designed to take humans to and from Mars.
所以尽管看到这个航天器里的网红渐渐过气让人感到惋惜
So although it will be sad to see this iconic space station come to an end,
我们还是要感谢它曾教会我们的海量的知识
we can appreciate the enormous amount of knowledge it has given us,
而我们也能继续期待未来更新、更令人激动的太空探索任务
and we can look forward to a new, exciting future of space exploration.
感谢Primal Space的帮助每个视频撰写文稿查找资料的赞助者
Thank you to the Primal Space patrons who helped to write and research each video.
如果你想赞助Primal Space频道并加入我们专有Discord群
If you'd like to contribute to Primal Space and join our exclusive Discord.
请访问patreon.com/primalspace
please visit patreon.com/primalspace
满100名赞助者后会再抽一位赠送土星五号乐高玩具
where we will be giving away another Saturn V Lego Set once we reach 100 patrons.
所以记得关注，方便我们讨论、学习所有和太空有关的知识
So make sure you've subscribed, so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space.
非常感谢您的观看，我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching, and I'll see you in the next video.